Brian Brown II

Full-Stack Web Developer

Alexandria, VA (703) 867-7737 bkbrown.dev@gmail.com github.com/bkeithbii

RELEVANT EXPERIENCE

General Assembly, Washington, DC — Software Engineering Scholar

January 2020 - April 2020

Three-month, 500-hour full-time and full-stack Software Engineering program providing experience with the most contemporary front- and back-end programming languages, tools, and methodologies. Developed and created a portfolio of individually and collaboratively focused in-class projects, including:

- **Simon** Memory game played by displaying a randomized sequence of buttons for the user to repeat by interacting with a unique game board.
 - o HTML | CSS | JAVASCRIPT
- TrendFlix Collaborated with 3 engineers to plan and create a MERN website showing the current week's highest trending movies and tv shows, with the capability of adding them to a personal watch list.
 - HTML | CSS | JAVASCRIPT | MONGODB | EXPRESS | NODEJS | SWAGGER

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Network for Good, Washington, DC — Business Development Representative

July 2019 - December 2019

Presented sales pitches, product reports, updates and best practices of the industry to 60–80 potential prospects daily in a way that promoted the company's mission, helping audiences identify a need for the product.

OrthoVirginia, Mclean, VA — Exercise Technician & Front Office Coordinator

February 2018 - July 2019

As the front office coordinator maintained the registration desk, answered phone lines, scheduled 100+ appointments, checked in/out 40-50 patients, verified insurance coverage and updated patient data daily.

As a technician held responsibility for coaching and queuing 40-50 patients daily through appropriate exercises, modalities and human exercise principles as related to their individual treatment assigned by the physical therapist.

PROFESSIONAL PROFILE

Full-stack web developer with a background in healthcare and sales business development. My unique experience enables me to examine problems systematically from a macro and micro perspective. I thrive in team settings, have a passion for learning new skills and improving the lives of others.

SKILLS

Programming Languages

JavaScript, Python, SQL, CSS, HTML

Platforms and Frameworks

React, Node, Express, Django, MongoDB, GIT, SASS

Other Skills

REST API's, Github, Mongoose, Agile, Heroku, Bootstrap, Storybook, Netlify, Peewee

Education

Software Engineering Immersive

General Assembly | Washington, DC | Jan 2020 -Apr 2020

Bachelor of Sports Medicine

Howard University | Washington, DC | Aug 2012 -May 2016